# **Scott Robenolt**

# Instrumentation and Electrical (I&E) Design Engineer

Haddonfield, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Scott-Robenolt/007f89e1a5d8f64d

Mr. Robenolt is an I&E Design Engineer with 34 years of experience in the design of instrumentation and electrical control systems for chemical process plants, refineries, power generating stations, and manufacturing facilities. His expertise includes the preparation of elementary wiring diagrams; interconnecting wiring diagrams; loop diagrams; instrument installation details; control panel arrangements; conduit and cable schedules; and instrument location and conduit routing plans. Mr. Robenolt has over 20 years of experience in, and is proficient using MicroStation Computer Aided Design Software and Microsoft Windows applications. Mr. Robenolt also has strong experience in the field, performing instrument loop checks and construction oversight.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Instrumentation and Electrical (I&E) Design Engineer

Jacobs Engineering / Sharp Design Inc. - Mount Laurel, NJ - June 1992 to June 2012 Jacobs Engineering, Mount Laurel, NJ (June 1992 to June 2012) Sharp Design Inc., Woodbury, NJ (June 1992 to Jacobs acquisition Dec. 2001)

Mr. Robenolt has 20 years experience with Jacobs Engineering and Sharp Design, having been involved in numerous projects both large and small, for refineries in Paulsboro NJ and Marcus Hook PA. Representative projects include:

- I&E Design Engineer for an Operator Shelter project consolidating three operator shelters (control rooms) into one multi-unit blast resistant operator shelter. This project included re-routing of instrumentation, control and data cables to the consolidated control room, relocation of three DCS consoles, design of three new emergency shut-down/annunciator panels, and changes to the existing unit shut-down interlock systems.
- I&E Design Engineer for a Clean Fuels project separating one process unit into two distinct units. This project included re-routing of instrumentation and control cables to a new remote instrument enclosure.
- I&E Design Engineer for a Sulfur Recovery Complex H2S Monitoring System upgrade. This project included the design for forty-two (42) locally mounted sensors, a control panel housing three 16-channel monitors in the unit control room, and interface to the DCS for danger, warning, and malfunction alarms.
- I&E Design Engineer for the re-instrumentation of an Ethylene Oxide Unit.

  This project involved the evaluation of the Unit Emergency Shut-Down System for compliance with client and industry standards, the renovation of the 120 volt shut-down interlocks and the replacement of shut-down related pneumatic instruments with electronic devices.

#### Resume

- I&E Design Engineer for the expansion and yield improvements to existing FCC and USGP process units. Responsibilities included design for instrumentation associated with upgrading or replacing numerous heat exchangers, vessels, pumps, and a new Flue Gas Cooler.
- I&E Design Engineer for the engineering and design of a refinery Process

  Heater Re-tube project, including burner control and safety interlock overhaul for two Coker Unit heaters.
- I&E Design Engineer for the engineering and design of a Reformer Naphtha Process Heater replacement. Responsibilities involved revision of the burner interlock systems.
- I&E Design Engineer for the I&E component of two pharmaceutical chemical facility vessel replacements. This project included: control panel design; two variable speed drives and the associated electrical distribution equipment; and design and implementation of digital controls.
- I&E Design Engineer for the engineering, design, and construction of an Off-Gas Sweetening Skid System for an asphalt refinery. This project involved the on-skid mechanical/piping and instrument/electrical systems, specification and procurement of all major equipment, instrumentation, and materials, and fabrication of the skids.
- I&E Designer for the engineering and design of a hydrocracking unit debottleneck project. Extensive re-work of a Honeywell TDC-3000 DCS was required, as was splitting LCN highways and interfacing two new turbine-driven compressor PLCs via PLC Gateways. Heater fuel gas and emergency shutdown relay logic was also extensively revised.
- I&E Design Engineer for the engineering and design of a crude unit upgrade project. This project incorporated major I&E improvements into the towers and heater.
- I&E Design Engineer for the engineering and design of a refinery-wide, tank farm DCS upgrade. Project included tie-in of a fiber optic LCN (and related equipment) to an operating, Honeywell TDC-3000 DCS central control room, and installation of new consoles in central and remote control rooms. The project also included the installation of a Honeywell Advanced Process Manager to replace an existing, on-line gasoline blender PLC.

## **Electrical / Instrumentation designer**

Fluor Daniel - Marlton, NJ - August 1990 to September 1991 Mobil Oil Corporation's Paulsboro Refinery DCS upgrade.

### Electrical designer

E.I. Dupont de Nemours & Co - Newark, DE - June 1988 to July 1990 Biomedical products manufacturing, and nylon fiber production machinery.

## **Electrical Designer**

ADEC - Swarthmore, PA - August 1987 to May 1988

Small arms ammunition manufacturing machinery.

## **Electrical designer**

Ferag Inc - Bristol, PA - November 1986 to July 1987

Newspaper conveying equipment.

## **Electrical designer**

Scott Paper Co - Philadelphia, PA - January 1984 to October 1986

Paper product manufacturing facilities.

## **Electrical drafter**

Grim Corp - Medford, NJ - November 1983 to December 1983

Naval communications equipment.

#### **Electrical drafter**

Stone & Webster Engineering Corp - Cherry Hill, NJ - September 1979 to April 1983

Nuclear & fossil fuel power generating station projects.

#### **Electrical drafter**

Beaumont Birch Co - Pennsauken, NJ - June 1978 to September 1979

Ash and Coal conveying and storage systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

High School / Vocational - in residential, commercial, and industrial wiring methods; relay logic; motor control; and the requirements of the National Electric Code.

Camden County Vocational & Technical School - Berlin, NJ 1978

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC), Valid until Nov. 20, 2013